Rockhill, William Woodville, 1854-1914. William Woodville Rockhill papers (MS Am 2121): Guide.
William Woodville Rockhill papers,
1826-1941.
Houghton Library, Harvard College Library, Harvard University
MS Am 2121
Rockhill, William Woodville, 1854-1914.
34 boxes, 6 card file boxes, and 8 volumes (18 linear ft.)
Papers of American scholar-diplomat William Woodville Rockhill.
*46M-386 and *46M-386A-T. Gift of Courtland Hoppin, Esq., 131 East 94th St., New York, N.Y.; received: 1947.
*46M-386U. Gift of Yale University Library, 1980.
There are no restrictions on physical access to this material.
Rockhill was an American scholar-diplomat known especially as the first Westerner to befriend and advise a Dalai Lama of Tibet. He was U.S. Minister to Greece, Romania, Serbia, China, Russia, and Turkey.
Organized into the following series:
I. Correspondence and other papers
II. Unidentified material
III. Miscellanea
IV. Diaries, account book, and commonplace book
V. Letterbooks
VI. Card index to these papers
Chiefly letters to William Woodville Rockhill from various correspondents including: Henry Adams, Horace Newton Allen, Samuel Beal, Henri Cordier, Chandra Das Sarat, William Foster, Alfred Edward Hippisley, Friedrich Hirth, Sir John Scott Keltie, Richard Olney, Theodore Roosevelt, Reinhold Rost, Thomas Watters, James Harrison Wilson, and John Russell Young. Also contains speeches and articles by William Woodville Rockhill and his diaries from 1908 to 1914. There is correspondence of Thomas C. Rockhill and a commonplace book about him. Finally, there are letterbooks with copies of typed letters to various people and an account book belonging to Edward Augustus Rockhill, among other materials.
- I. Correspondence and other papers
  - Abbott, Gordon, 1863-1937. Typed L.s.(Gordon Abbott) to [William] [Woodville] Rockhill; Boston, 19 May 1897., (1); 1l.
  - Abbott, Gordon, 1863-1937. Typed L.s.(Gordon Abbott) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; Boston, 5 Jun 1897., (2); 2l.
  - Abbott, Gordon, 1863-1937. A.L.s.(Gordon Abbott) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; Boston, 25 Jul [1900]., (3); ([2]p.)
  - Abe, Moritaro. Mimeographed Translation of Supplementary Agreement between Japan and China concerning the Jsin-Feng and Chi-Ch'ang Railway; Peking, 12 Nov 1908., (4); 4l.
  - Adams, Brooks, 1848-1927. A.L.s.(Brooks Adams) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; Quincy, 2 Jun 1897., (5)
  - Adams, Brooks, 1848-1927. A.L.s.(Brooks Adams) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; Quincy, 10 Jul 1897., (6); ([2]p.)
  - Adams, Brooks, 1848-1927. A.L.s.(Brooks Adams) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; Quincy, 14 Jun 1899., (7); ([3]p.)
  - Adams, Brooks, 1848-1927. A.L.s.(Brooks Adams) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; Quincy, 4 Jul 1899., (8); ([3]p.)
  - Adams, Brooks, 1848-1927. A.L.s.(Brooks Adams) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; Quincy, 11 Jul 1899., (9); ([3]p.)
  - Adams, Brooks, 1848-1927. Typed L.s.(Brooks Adams) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; Quincy, 13 Jul 1902., (10); 1l.
  - Adams, Brooks, 1848-1927. A.L.s.(Brooks Adams) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; Boston, 21 Dec 1902., (11); 1l.
  - Adams, Brooks, 1848-1927. Typed L.s.(Brooks Adams) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; Quincy, 28 May 1905., (12); 1l.
  - Adams, Brooks 1848-1927. Typed L.s.(Brooks Adams) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; Quincy, 23 Oct 1903., (13); 2l.
  - Adams, Brooks, 1848-1927. A.L.s.(Brooks Adams) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; Asheville, 4 Mar 1907., (14); ([2]p.)
  - Adams, Henry, 1838-1918. A.L.s.(Henry Adams) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; [Washington] 11 Mar 1890., (15); ([2]p.)
  - Adams, Henry, 1838-1918. A.L.s.(Henry Adams) to [William] [Woodville] Rockhill; [Washington] [10 Jul 1890], (16); ([3]p.)
  - Adams, Henry, 1838-1918. A.L.s.(Henry Adams) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; [Washington] 17 May 1895., (17); ([4]p.)
  - Adams, Henry, 1838-1918. A.L.s.(Henry Adams) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; [Washington] 1896., (18); ([1]p.)
  - Adams, Henry, 1838-1918. A.L.s.(Henry Adams) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; [Washington] [10 Mar? 1896], (19); ([2]p.)
  - Adams, Henry, 1838-1918. A.L.s.(Henry Adams) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; Paris, 10 Sep 1896., (20); ([4]p.)
    Enclosed: Newspaper clipping in French.
  - Adams, Henry, 1838-1918. A.L.s.(Henry Adams) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; Paris, 12 Jun 1897., (21); ([4]p.)
  - Adams, Henry, 1838-1918. A.L.s.(H. A.) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; Vienna, 10 May 1898., (22); ([4]p.)
  - Adams, Henry, 1838-1918. A.L.s.(Henry Adams) to "Gentle Tartar" [i.e. William Woodville Rockhill]; London, 12 Jun 1898., (23); ([7]p.)
  - Adams, Henry, 1838-1918. A.L.s.(Henry Adams) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; Ashford, 24 Aug [1898]., (24); ([4]p.)
  - Adams, Henry, 1838-1918. A.L.s.(H. A.) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; Ashford, 15 Sep [1898]., (25); ([4]p.)
  - Adams, Henry, 1838-1918. A.L.s.(H. A.) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; Aberdeenshire, 31 Oct [1898]., (26); ([8]p.)
  - Adams, Henry, 1838-1918. A.L.s.(Henry Adams) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; [Washington] 23 Dec 1898., (27); ([8]p.)
  - Adams, Henry, 1838-1918. A.L.(unsigned) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; [n.p.] 16 Feb 1899., (28); ([8]p.)
  - Adams, Henry, 1838-1918. A.L.s.(Henry Adams) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; Paris, 6 Apr [1899]., (29); ([4]p.)
  - Adams, Henry, 1838-1918. A.L.s.(Henry Adams) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; Paris, 8 Sep [1899]., (30); ([4]p.)
  - Adams, Henry, 1838-1918. A.L.s.(Henry Adams) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; [Washington] [1900], (31); ([2]p.)
  - Adams, Henry, 1838-1918. A.L.s.(Henry Adams) to [William] [Woodville] Rockhill; [Washington] 22 Apr 1900., (32); ([2]p.)
  - Adams, Henry, 1838-1918. A.L.s.(Henry Adams) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; Paris, 12 Jul 1900., (33); ([8]p.)
  - Adams, F. O. A.L.s.(F. O. Adams) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; Berne, 6 Jan 1884., (34); ([2]p.)
  - Adams, F. O. A.L.s.(F. O. Adams) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; Berne, 2 Feb [1884]., (35); ([1]p.)
  - Adams, F. O. A.L.s.(F. O. Adams) to [William Woodville] Rockhill;; Berne, 1 Dec 1886., (36); ([2]p.)
  - Adams, Herbert Baxter, 1850-1901. A.L.s.(H. B. Adams) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; Baltimore, 20 Mar 1890., (37); ([4]p.)
  - Adee, Alvey Augustus, 1842-1924. Typed L.s.(Alvey A.Adee) to [William] [Woodville] Rockhill; Washington, 19 Nov 1897., (37a); 3l.
  - Adee, Alvey Augustus, 1842-1924. A.L.s.(Alvey A. Adee) to [William] [Woodville] Rockhill; Washington, 31 Mar 1898., (38); 2l.
  - Adee, Alvey Augustus, 1842-1924. A.L.s.(A. A. A.) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; [Washington] 17 Sep 1896., (39); 3l.
  - Adee, Alvey Augustus, 1842-1924. A.L.s.(A. A. A.) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; [Washington] 6 Sep [1898], (40); 1l.
    Includes: Mr. Martin's notes of the assurances given by Russia and Germany. 4l.
  - Adee, Alvey Augustus, 1842-1924. A.L.s.(Alvey A. Adee) to [William] [Woodville] Rockhill; Washington, 21 Sep 1898., (41); ([4]p.)
  - Adee, Alvey Augustus, 1842-1924. Typed L.s.(Alvey A. Adee) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; Washington, 3 Feb. 1898., (42); ([4]p.)
  - Adee, Alvey Augustus, 1842-1924. Telegram form s.(Adee) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; Washington, 4 Apr 1899., (43); 1l.
  - Adee, Alvey Augustus, 1842-1924. Typed Memorandum s.(Alvey A. Adee) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; [Washington] 21 Feb 1900., (44); 1l.
  - Adee, Alvey Augustus, 1842-1924. Typed Memorandum s.(A. A. Adee) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; [Washington] 13 Mar 1900., (45); 1l.
  - Adee, Alvey Augustus, 1842-1924. Typed Copy of Telegram received in cipher (c.c.) to Secretary of State s.(White); London, 12 Mar 1900., (46); 1l.
  - Adee, Alvey Augustus, 1842-1924. Typed L.s.(Alvey A. Adee) to [William] [Woodville] Rockhill; Washington, 20 Nov 1901., (47); 1l.
  - Adee, Alvey Augustus, 1842-1924. Typed L.s.(Alvey A. Adee) to [William] [Woodville] Rockhill; [Washington] 6 Dec 1901., (48); 1l.
  - Adee, Alvey Augustus, 1842-1924. Typed L.s.(Alvey A. Adee) to [William] [Woodville] Rockhill; Washington, 22 Jan 1902., (49); 1l.
  - Adee, Alvey Augustus, 1842-1924. Typed L.s.(Alvey A. Adee) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; Washington, 9 Jul 1902., (50); 1l.
  - Adee, Alvey Augustus, 1842-1924. Typed L.s.(Alvey A. Adee) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; Washington, 11 Oct 1902., (51); 1l.
  - Adee, Alvey Augustus, 1842-1924. Typed L.s.(Alvey A. Adee) to [William] [Woodville] Rockhill and W. P. Armstrong; Washington, 15 Jul 1903., (52); 1l.
  - Adee, Alvey Augustus, 1842-1924. Typed L.s.(Alvey A. Adee) to [William] [Woodville] Rockhill; Washington, 11 Aug 1903., (53); 1l.
  - Adee, Alvey Augustus, 1842-1924. A.L.s.(Alvey A. Adee) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; Washington, 8 Aug 1905., (54); [2]p.
  - Adler, Cyrus, 1863-1940. Typed L.s.(Cyrus Adler) to William [Woodville] Rockhill; Washington, 10 Nov 1905., (55); 2l.
  - Adler, Cyrus, 1863-1940. Typed L.s.(Cyrus Adler) to [William] [Woodville] Rockhill; Washington, 27 Feb 1906., (56); 2l.
  - Agassiz, Alexander, 1835-1910. A.L.s.(A. Agassiz) to [William Woodville Rockhill]; Cambridge, 12 Dec [18]95., (57); ([1]p.)
  - Aglen, E. A. A. L.s.(E. A. Aglen) to [William Woodville Rockhill]; Peking, 16 Mar 1914., (58); ([1]p.)
    Enclosure: Typed memo of Customs average rates for two years.
  - Aglen, E. A. Typed Inspector General's Memorandum; Peking, 7 Nov 1912., (59); 4l.
  - Alexander, Eben. A.L.s.(Eben Alexander) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; North Carolina, 24 Jul 1900., (60); ([1]p.)
  - Alexander, Eben. A.L.s.(Eben Alexander) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; Chapel Hill, 15 Mar 1905., (61); 1l.
  - Allen, A A A.L.s.(A.A.Allen) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; [n.p.] 22 Jun 1897., (62a); ([4]p.)
  - Alishan, Ghevont M., 1820- A.L.s.(P. Leonce M. Alishan) to [William Woodville Rockhill]; Venice, 7 Jun 1898., (62); ([1]p.)
    In French.
  - Allen, Edgar Pierce. Typed L.(c.c.)s.(E. P. Allen) to Dr. D. C. Gilman; [n.p.] 8 Jun [?], (63); 4l.
  - Allen, Edgar Pierce. A.L.s.(Edgar Pierce Allen) to [William] [Woodville] Rockhill; Tientsin, 12 Jun 1905., (64); 3l.
  - Allen, Horace Newton, 1858-1932. A.L.s.(H.N.Allen) to [Willima Woodville] Rockhill; Seoul, 12 Jun 1891., (64a); ([4]p.)
  - Allen, Horace Newton, 1858-1932. A.L.s.(H. N. Allen) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; Seoul, 12 May 1892., (65); ([8]p.)
  - Allen, Horace Newton, 1858-1932. A.L.s.(H.N.Allen) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; Seoul, 25 May 1894., (65a); ([4]p.)
  - Allen, Horace Newton, 1858-1932. A.L.s.(Allen) to [William] [Woodville] Rockhill; Seoul, 3 Jul 1894., (65b); ([4]p.)
  - Allen, Horace Newton, 1858-1932. A.L.s.(H.N.Allen) to [William] [Woodville] Rockhill; Seoul, 17 Aug [1894]., (65c); ([4]p.)
  - Allen, Horace Newton, 1858-1932. A.L.s.(H.N.Allen) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; Seoul, 14 Sep 1894., (65d); ([4]p.)
  - Allen, Horace Newton, 1858-1932. A.L.s.(H. N. Allen) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; Seoul, 5 Mar 1895., (66); [2]p.
  - Allen, Horace Newton, 1858-1932. A.L.s.(H.N.Allen) to [William] [Woodville] Rockhill; Seoul, 2 May 1895., (66a); ([4]p.)
  - Allen, Horace Newton, 1858-1932. A.L.s.(H.N.Allen) to [William] [Woodville] Rockhill; Seoul, 11 Jun [1895]., (66b); ([4]p.)
  - Allen, Horace Newton, 1858-1932. A.L.s.(H.N.Allen) to [William] [Woodville] Rockhill; Seoul, 23 Jul 1895., (66c); ([4]p.)
  - Allen, Horace Newton, 1858-1932. A.L.s.(H.N.Allen) to [William] [Woodville] Rockhill; Seoul, 27 Jul [1895]., (66d); ([2]p.)
  - Allen. Horace Newton, 1858-1932. A.L.s.(H.N.Allen) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; Seoul, 18 Sep 1895., (66e); ([4]p.)
  - Allen, Horace Newton, 1858-1932. A.L.s.(H.N.Allen) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; Seoul, 15 Oct 1895., (66f); [2]p.
  - Allen, Horace Newton, 1858-1932. A.L.s.(H.N.Allen) to [William] [Woodville] Rockhill; Seoul, 16 Dec 1895., (66g); ([3]p.)
    Enclosure: A.L.s.(H.N.Allen) to W[illiam] W[oodville] Rockhill; Seoul, 2 Dec 1895. ([4]p.)
  - Allen, Horace Newton, 1858-1932. A.L.s.(H.N.Allen) to [William] [Woodville] Rockhill; Seoul, 29 Dec 1895., (66h); 4l.
  - Allen, Horace Newton, 1858-1932. A.L.s.(H.N.Allen) to [William] [Woodville] Rockhill; Seoul, 3 Jun 1896., (66i); ([4]p.)
  - Allen, Horace Newton, 1858-1932. A.L.s.(H.N.Allen) to [William] [Woodville] Rockhill; Seoul, 25 Jun 1896., (66j); ([6]p.)
  - Allen, Horace Newton, 1858-1932. A.L.s.(H.N.Allen) to [William] [Woodville] Rockhill; Seoul, 3 Jun [1896]., (66k); ([4]p.)
  - Allen, Horace Newton, 1858-1932. A.L.s.(H.N.Allen) to [William] [Woodville] Rockhill; Seoul, 21 Jun [1896]., (66l); ([7]p.)
  - Allen, Horace Newton, 1858-1932. A.L.s.(H.N.Allen) to [William] [Woodville] Rockhill; Seoul, 13 Jul [1896]., (66m); ([4]p.)
  - Allen, Horace Newton, 1858-1932. Typed L.s.(H.N.Allen) to [ ? ] Wilson; Seoul, 11 Oct 1897., (66n); 2l.
  - Allen, Horace Newton, 1858-1932. Typed L.s.(H. N. Allen) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; Seoul Korea, 30 Jan 1898., (67); 3l.
  - Allen, Horace Newton, 1858-1932. A.L.s.(H. N. Allen) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; Seoul Korea, 29 Feb [1898]., (68); ([4]p.)
  - Allen, Horace Newton, 1858-1932. Typed L.s.(H. N. Allen) to [William Woodville]Rockhill; Seoul Korea, 15 Feb 1899., (69); 1l.
  - Allen, Horace Newton, 1858-1932. Typed L.s.(H. N. Allen) to [William] [Woodville] Rockhill; Seoul, Korea, 23 Oct 1899., (70); 1l.
  - Allen, Horace Newton, 1858-1932. A.L.s.(H. N. Allen) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; Seoul Korea, 29 Jul 1900., (71); 3l.
  - Allen, Horace Newton, 1858-1932. Typed L.s.(H. N. Allen) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; Chemulpo, 8 Aug 1900., (72); 1l.
  - Allen, Horace Newton, 1858-1932. Typed L.s.(H. N. Allen) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; Seoul Korea, 23 Oct 1899., (73); ([4]p.)
  - Allen, Horace Newton, 1858-1932. Typed L.s.(H. N. Allen) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; Seoul Korea, 28 Feb 1901., (74); ([4]p.)
  - Allen, Horace Newton, 1858-1932. Typed L.s.(H. N. Allen) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; Seoul, Korea, 13 Mar 1901., (75); [2]p.
  - Allen, Horace Newton, 1858-1932. Typed L.s.(H. N. Allen) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; Seoul, Korea, 24 Mar 1901., (76); [2]p.
  - Allen, Horace Newton, 1858-1932. A.L.s.(H. N. Allen) to [William] [Woodville] Rockhill; Nagasaki, 23 Mar 1902., (77); ([8]p.)
  - Allen, Horace Newton, 1858-1932. Typed L.s.(H. N. Allen) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; Seoul, Korea, 4 Jan 1904., (78); 4l.
  - Allen, Horace Newton, 1858-1932. Typed L.s.(H. N. Allen) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; Seoul, Korea, 19 Apr 1904., (79); 1l.
  - Allen, Horace Newton, 1858-1932. Typed L.s.(H. N. Allen) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; Seoul, Korea, 6 May 1904., (80); 3l.
  - Allen, Horace Newton, 1858-1932. Typed L.s.(H. N. Allen) to [William] [Woodville] Rockhill; Seoul, Korea, 25 Aug 1904., (81); 2l.
  - Allen, Horace Newton, 1858-1932. Typed L.s.(H. N. Allen) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; Seoul, Korea, 21 Mar 1905., (82); 1l.
  - Allen, Thomas G. A.L.s.(Thos. G. Allen, Jr.) to [William] [Woodville] Rockhill; New York, 6 Mar 1896., (83); ([1]p.)
  - Allison, M. T. A.L.s.(M. T. Allison) to [William] [Woodville] Rockhill; Geneve, 17 Oct [1913], (84); ([4]p.)
  - Allison, M. T. A.L.s.(M. T. Allison) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; Geneve, 18 Nov [1913]., (85); ([4]p.)
  - Alward, Mrs. George H. A.L.s.(Mrs. George H. Alward) to William Woodville Rockhill; South Bend, Indiana, 5 Nov 1808 [i.e. should be 1908], (86); 3l.
  - American company, Shanghai. A.L.s.(T. C. White) to [William] [Woodville] Rockhill; Shanghai, 12 May 1908., (87); 1l.
  - Ammen, Daniel, 1819-1898. Typed L.s.(Daniel Ammen) to [William] Woodville Rockhill; Washington, 34 Dec 1889., (88); ([4]p.)
  - Ammen, Daniel, 1819-1898. Typed L.s.(Daniel Ammen) to J. M. Rusk; Ammendale, 24 Dec 1889., (89); 1l.
  - Anderson, F. Typed Copy of L.s.(F. Anderson) to Ilbert Co.; Shanghai, 28 May 1904., (90); 1l.
  - Anagarika Dharmapala. Typed L.s.(The Anagarika Dharmapala) to [William] [Woodville] Rockhill; Calcutta, India, 6 May 1908., (91); 2l.
  - Andonian, Hagop S. A.L.s.(H. S. Andonian) to [?]; [n.p., 191-?], (92); ([4]p.)
    The first part of this letter is wanting.
  - Andonian, Hagop S. A.L.s.(H. S. Andonian) to "My dear Chief"; Constantinople, 19 Sep 1913., (93); ([4]p.)
  - Andonian, Hagop S. A.L.s.(H. S. Andonian) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; Constantinople, 11 Dec 1913., (94); ([7]p.)
  - Andonian, Hagop S. A.L.s.(H. S. Andonian) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; Constantinople, 24 Mar 1914., (95); ([4]p.)
  - Andonian, Hagop S. A.L.s.(H. S. Andonian) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; Constantinople, 31 Aug 1914., (96); ([4]p.)
  - Angell, James Burrell, 1829-1916. A.L.s.(James B.Angell) to [William] [Woodville] Rockhill; Constantinople, 29 Dec 1897., (96a); ([4]p.)
  - Angell, James Burrill, 1829-1916. A.L.s.(James B. Angell) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; Constantinople, 1 Apr 1898., (97); ([4]p.)
  - Angell, James Burrill, 1829-1916. A.L.s.(James B. Angell) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; Ann Arbor, 20 Jul 1900., (98); ([3]p.)
  - Angell, James Burrill, 1829-1916. A.L.s.(James B. Angell) to [William] [Woodville] Rockhill; Ann Arbor, 29 Mar 1905., (99); ([3]p.)
  - Angell, James Burrill, 1829-1916. A.L.s.(James B. Angell) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; Ann Arbor, 16 May 1906., (100); [3]p.
  - Angell, James Burrill, 1829-1916. Typed L.s.(James B. Angell) to William [Woodville] Rockhill; Ann Arbor, 13 Oct 1906., (101); 1l.
  - Angell, James Burrill, 1829-1916. Typed L.s.(James B. Angell) to William [Woodville] Rockhill; Ann Arbor, 29 Jan 1908., (102); 1l.
  - Armstrong, W. P. A.L.(unsigned) to L. M. Shaw; Washington, Aug 1903., (103); ([4]p.)
  - Armstrong, W. P. A.L.s.(W. P. Armstrong) to [William] [Woodville] Rockhill; Washington, [Aug 1903], (104); ([3]p.)
  - Armstrong, W. P. A.L.s.(W. P.Armstrong) to [William] [Woodville] Rockhill; Shanghai, 3 Nov [1903]., (105); ([4]p.)
  - Armstrong, W. P. A.L.s.(W. P. Armstrong) to [William] [Woodville] Rockhill; Shanghai, 6 Nov [1903]., (106); ([4]p.)
  - Armstrong, W. P. A.L.s.(W. P. Armstrong) to [William] [Woodville] Rockhill; Shanghai, 17 Nov 1903., (107); ([4]p.)
  - Arnell, Charles John. Typed L.s.(C. J. Arnell) to [William] [Woodville] Rockhill; [Washington] 20 Jul 1912., (108); ([3]p.)
  - Arnell, Charles John. A.L.s.(C. J. Arnell) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; [Washington] 25 Sep 1912., (109); ([2]p.)
  - Arnell, Charles John. Typed L.s.(C. J. Arnell) to [William Woodville]Rockhill; [Washington] 10 Jan 1913., (110); ([2]p.)
  - Arnell, Charles John. Typed L.s.(C. J. Arnell) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; [Washington] 10 Aug 1913., (111); ([2]p.)
  - Arnell, Charles John. A.L.s.(C. J. Arnell) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; Tokyo, 14 Nov 1913., (112); ([4]p.)
  - Arnell, Charles John. Typed L.s.(C. J. Arnell) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; Tokyo, 28 Mar 1914., (113); ([3]p.)
  - Arendt, Carl, 1838-1902. A.L.s.(C. Arendt) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; [n.p., n.d.], (114); ([3]p.)
  - Arendt, Carl, 1838-1902. A.L.s.(C.Arendt) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; [n.p., 188-?], (115); ([7]p.)
  - Arendt, Carl, 1838-1902. A.L.s.(C.Arendt) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; [n.p.] 5 Mar [1886]., (115a); ([8]p.)
  - Arendt, Carl, 1838-1902. A.L.s.(C. Arendt) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; Peking, 28 Sep [1886]., (116); ([7]p.)
  - Arnold, Julean Herbert, 1875- A.L.s.(Julean H. Arnold) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; Fuchau, 22 Mar [1906]., (117); 39l.
  - Arnold, Julean Herbert, 1875- Typed L.s.(Julean H. Arnold) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; Fuchau, 23 Apr 1906., (118); 9l.
  - Arnold, Julean Herbert, 1875- Typed L.s.(Julean H. Arnold) to [William] [Woodville]Rockhill; Shanghai, 23 Jul 1906., (119); ([2]p.)
  - Arnold, Julean Herbert, 1875- A.L.s.(Julean H. Arnold) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; Formosa, 30 Mar 1907., (120); ([4]p.)
  - Arriaguy?, St. Lazo? A.L.s. to [William Woodville] Rockhill; Formosa, 20 July 1900., (120a)
  - Association royale de geographie Neulandaise. A.L.s.(Levensveldt) to [William] Woodville Rockhill; Amsterdam, 29 May 1897., (121); ([2]p.)
  - Atwood, I. J. A.L.s.(I. J. Atwood) to [William] [Woodville] Rockhill; Tai Yuen Fu, 4 Oct [1901]., (122); ([2]p.)
  - Baddeley, John Frederick, 1854-1940. A.L.s.(John F. Baddeley) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; St. Petersburg, 28 Nov 1911., (123); ([4]p.)
  - Baddeley, John Frederick, 1854-1940. A.L.s.(John F.Baddeley) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; London, 26 Dec 1911., (123a); ([4]p.)
  - Bailey, Ted. A.L.s.(Ted Bailey) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; [n.p.] 11 Jun 1893., (124); ([2]p.)
  - Bailey, F. M. A.L.s. to [William Woodville] Rockhill; 12 Aug. 1911., (124a)
  - Bailie, Joseph. Typed L.s.(Joseph Bailie) to David Fairchild; Nanking, 17 Aug 1914., (125); 3l.
  - Bainbridge, William E. A.L.s.(W. E. Bainbridge) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; Caracas, 14 Nov 1903., (126); [2]p.
  - Baker, E. Carleton. Typed L.s.(E. Carleton Baker) to William [Woodville] Rockhill; Washington, 28 Jul 1909., (127); 1l.
  - Baker, E. Colborne. A.L.s.(E. Colborne Baker) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; Soul, 16 Jan 1886., (128); ([4]p.)
  - Baker, E. Colborne. A.L.s.(E. Colborne Baker) to [William Woodville] Rockhillp Soul, 6 Feb 1886., (129); ([4]p.)
  - Baker, E. Colborne. A.L.s.(E. Colborne Baker) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; Soul, 2 Apr [1886]., (130); ([4]p.)
  - Baker, Marcus, 1849-1903. Typed L.s.(Marcus Baker) to [William] [Woodville] Rockhill; Washington, 19 Feb 1890., (131); 2l.
  - Baker, Orlando H. A.L.s.(Orlando H. Baker) to [William] [Woodville] Rockhill; Indianola, 27 Feb 1897., (132); ([4]p.)
  - Bakhmeteff, G. A. card s.(G. Bakhmeteff) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; [St. Petersburg, before July, 1911], (133); 1l.
  - Bakhmeteff, Mary. A. cards s.(Mary Bakhmeteff) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; [n.p., n.d.], (134); 3l.
  - Bakhmeteff, Mary. A.L.s.(M. B.) to [Edith (Perkins)]Rockhill; [n.p., 1911], (135); ([4]p.)
  - Bakhmeteff, Mary. A. card s.(M. B.) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; [n.p., 1911], (136); [2]p.
  - Baldwin, Elbert F. Typed L.s.(Elbert F.Baldwin) to William Woodville Rockhill; 25 Jun 1914., (136a); 1l.
  - Baldwin, James Mark, 1861- Typed L.s.(J. Mark Baldwin) to [William] [Woodville] Rockhill; New York, 28 Oct 1914., (137); 1l.
  - Bandinel, J J Frederick A.L.s.(J.J.Fredk Bandinel) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; Newchwang, 29 Jun 1886., (137a); [6]p.
  - Bandinel, J J Frederick A.L.s.(J.J.Fredk Bandinel) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; Newchwang, 15 Jul 1886., (137b); 1l.
  - Barker, Wharton, 1846-1921. A.L.s.(Wharton Barker) to William Woodville Rockhill; Philadelphia, 7 Apr 1903., (138); [4]p.
  - Barnes, Thurlow Weed, 1853- A.L.s.(Thurlow Weed Barnes) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; Shanghai, 3 Jun 1906., (139); 1l.
  - Barnes, Thurlow Weed, 1853- A.L.s.(Thurlow Weed Barnes) to [William] [Woodville] Rockhill; New York, 1 Feb 1907., (140); 2l.
    With autograph P.S.s.(T.W.B.)
  - Barnes, Thurlow Weed, 1853- Typed L.s.(Thurlow Weed Barnes) to [William] [Woodville] Rockhill; New York, 3 Mar 1909., (141); 2l.
  - Barot, Alexandre. A.L.s.(Barot) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; Paris, 31 Jul 1912., (142); ([2]p.)
  - Barrett, John, 1866- Telegram s.(John Barrett) to [William] [Woodville] Rockhill; New York, 20 Jul [1900]., (143); 1l.
  - Barrett, John, 1866- Typed L.s.(John Barrett) to [William Woodville] Rockhill; Mexico City, 21 Oct 1901., (144); 3l.
  - Barrett, John, 1866- Telegram s.(Barrett) to [Edith (Perkins)] Rockhill; Washington, 9 Dec [?], (145); 1l.
  - Barrett, John, 1866- Typed Article entitled "William Woodville Rockhill, An Appreciation"; [n.p., n.d.], (146); 4l.
  - Barrows, Samuel June, 1845-1909. Typed L.s.(S. J. Barrows) to William [Woodville] Rockhill; Dorchester, 23 Jun 1897., (147); 1l.
  - Baumgetz, C. A.L.s.(C. Baumgetz) to [William Woodville Rockhill]; Batavia, 31 Dec 1886., (148); ([4]p.)